
	
	<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

	<bookstore>

		<book>
		  <title lang="en">Harry Potter</title>
		  <price>29.99</price>
		</book>

		<book>
		  <title lang="en">Learning XML</title>
		  <price>39.95</price>
		</book>

	</bookstore> 

<!--
	XPath Axes
	An axis defines a node-set relative to the current node.

	AxisName	

		ancestor				Selects all ancestors (parent, grandparent, etc) of the current node
		ancestor-or-self		Selects all ancestors (parent, grandparent, etc) of the current node and the current node itself
		attribute				Selects all attributes of the current node
		child					Selects all children of the current node
		descendant				Selects all descendants (children,grandchildren, etc) of the current node
		descendant-or-self		Selects all descendants (children,grandchildren, etc) of the current node and the current node itself
		following				Selects everything in the document after the closing tag of the current node
		following-sibling		Selects all siblings after the current node.
		namespace				Selects all namespace nodes of the current node
		parent					Selects the parent of the current node
		preceding				Selects all nodes that appear before the current node in the document, except ancestors, attribute nodes and namespace nodes
		preceding-sibling		Selects all siblings before the current node
		self 					Selects the current node


	Location Path Expression
		A location path can be absolute or relative.

		An absolute path starts with a slash (/) and a relative location path does not. In both cases the location path consists of one or more steps,
		each seperated by a slash:

		An absoulte location path
			/step/step/...

		A relative location path
			step/step/...

	Each step is evaluated against the nodes in the current node-set.

	A step consists of:
		an axis(defines the tree-relationship between the selected nodes and the current node)
		a node-test (identifies a node within an axis)
		zero or more predicates (to further refine the selected node set)

		child::book 			Selects all book nodes that are children of the current node
		attribute::lang 		Selects the lang attribute of the current node
		child::*				Selects all element children of the current node
		attribute::*			Selects all attributes of the current node
		child::text()			Selects all text node children of the current node
		child::node()			Selects all children of the current node
		descendant::book 		Selects all book decendants of the current node
		ancestor::book 			Selects all book ancestors of the current node
		ancestor-or-self::book 	Selects all book ancestors of the current node - and the current as well if it is a book node
		child::*/child::price 	Selects all price grandchildren of the current node

